# **AJAY GHIMIRE**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### PERSONAL INFO

#### **ADDRESS**

7-9 Churchill Avenue, Strathfield, NSW 2135

# PHONE

0404286785

#### **EMAIL**

ajayghimire1998@gmail.com

#### LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajay ahimire/

#### **PORTFOLIO WEBSITE**

https://ajayghimire1998.github.io /ajay-ghimire/#/

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### LANGUAGES

- JavaScript
- Ruby
- Java (Actively Learning)
- HTML / CSS

# FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES

- React
- Redux
- Express.js
- Ruby on Rails

# **DATABASES**

- MvSQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB

#### **TOOLS**

- Git Source Control
- AWS (Basic)
- VS Code and Eclipse
- Postman
- ChatGPT
- Microsoft Office
- Adobe After Effects

# **PROFILE**

An aspiring junior developer with a solid 4-year foundation in software development from a bachelor's degree, combined with a software engineering bootcamp, and sustained self-directed study and professional development. Honed impressive problem-solving and creative thinking through continuous academic projects development. Driven by a desire and an unwavering commitment to leveraging technology for social good, seeking to pursue a fulfilling career in software development.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Software Engineering Transform Academy Xi



Sydney

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

#### **COURSEWORK**

- Front-end Web Development with JavaScript, React and HTML / CSS
- Back-end Web Development with Ruby on Rails
- Object-Oriented Programming with JavaScript and Ruby
- Database Systems with MySQL and PostgreSQL

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

- WITH LOVE FROM HOME: PostgreSQL, React, Ruby on Rails
- GOALS TO SCORE: MongoDB, Express, React, Node
- MEMEBOOK: Firebase, React, RESTful API (Reddit API, ImgFlip API)
- CRYPTOMANIA: Ruby, Nokogiri, Bundler
- PLAY MATES: Ruby on Rails
- MOVIE FINDER: JavaScript, RESTful API (OMDB API)

Bachelor of Information Technology and Systems (BITS) **Major: Software Development** 



Victorian Institute of Technology

Jul 2018 - Jul 2021

Sydney

#### **COURSEWORK**

- Programming Fundamentals
- Web Development
- **Database Management Systems**
- Systems Analysis and Design
- **Project Management**
- Professionalism and Ethics

# **ACADEMIC PROJECT**

COCINERO: C#, Xamarin

# **OTHER SKILLS**

- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Communication
- Adaptability and Flexibility
- Collaboration
- Project Management (Basic)

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English (Fluent)
- Hindi (Proficient)
- Nepali (Native)

# RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS

- React + Redux a
- Ruby 🗖
- Responsive Web Design

# ENROLLED & AWAITING CERTIFICATIONS

# AUSTRALIAN COMPUTER SOCIETY (ACS):

- Professional Environments (Currently Running)
- Professional Year Program (Completed)

# RELEVENT EXPERIENCE

# Web Developer Intern, Brand Easy Australia

Dec 2022 – Present

Campsie

- Collaborated with the development team to plan, develop, test, deploy, and maintain web applications.
- Participated in code reviews and documentation and contributed to the creation of technical documentation and user manuals.
- Worked with project managers to prioritize tasks and ensure timely delivery of projects.

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES

## **Retail Assistant, Chemist Warehouse**

Brookvale

Dec 2022 - Present

- Developed exposure to Data Management by managing customer transactions and financial records using point-of-sale software.
- Sharpened problem-solving skills by collaborating with a team to resolve product availability issues and ensure the store was fully stocked.
- Improved customer service by assisting customers with their purchases, providing product information and recommendations.

## Cook, Cho Cho San

Potts Point

Jan 2018 - Nov 2022

- Developed strong time management and multitasking skills by working in a fast-paced, high-pressure environment.
- Improved teamwork skills by collaborating with a team of chefs and servers to coordinate meal preparation and delivery,
- Demonstrated attention to detail and a commitment to quality by contributing to dishes preparation according to recipe and ensuring high quality presentation.

# **INTERESTS AND HOBBIES**

- Playing video games
- Playing guitar
- Watching sci-fi and dystopian TV shows
- Writing LinkedIn posts
- Solving LeetCode problems